Hello my friends, and welcome back.
In this section we're going to build this gorgeous app called the Quiz App.
This amazing app will fetch the data from a local database that we're going to build together.
And inside this database we'll create math table.
And inside this table we have records.
And the records are representing questions.
These questions will be fetched into Json response.
So we're going to transform our database data and records into Json response with the help of the API
that will create.
So we're going to create our own API in PHP language.
And don't worry I'll show you step by step how to create this API that transforms the database records
and the questions into Json response.
Then we're going to use our old friend retrofit to transform this Json response into Pojo.
Plain old Java objects to be displayed into the app UI.
This app will teach you how to create your local database.
MySQL.
How to create your own API, how to fetch the Json response from database, how to use retrofit to create
Java objects and display questions into Android app.
Of course I'm going to follow mVVM architecture Model view ViewModel in this app.
Moreover, I'll use data binding library.
So this is an amazing app and beautiful app that allows the user to select one choice.
So for example 35 question number two.
So we'll be directing the user to the results activity and displaying the scores one over two or the
total questions.