Welcome back.
In this video we're going to set up our local development environment.
We'll start by downloading Examp install it then creating our MySQL database.
Go to Apache friends.org website and select download.
Then select the installer according to your operating system.
I'll select this exam for windows.
Then run the installer.
Then open the Examp and Examp is a popular free and open source software stack that facilitates the
setup and management of a local development environment for web applications.
You can install similar softwares like Wamp and other softwares, but I like dealing with Examp.
Examp is mainly used for developing and testing web applications in your local computer before deploying
them to a live web server, and what we are interested in is Apache and MySQL.
Click start and then go to Chrome and type 127.0.0.1.
Or you can type localhost and click enter.
And here is the Examp dashboard.
And from this dashboard I will select phpMyAdmin.
phpMyAdmin is a popular open source, web based graphical user interface tool used for managing and
administering MySQL and MariaDB databases.
It allows users to interact with their databases through a web browser, making it easier to perform
various database related tasks without having to use the command line interface.
phpMyAdmin provides a user friendly interface for creating, modifying, and deleting databases, tables,
and fields within those tables, and for that I use this phpMyAdmin.
I'll create a new database and the new database will be named as my quiz DB.
Click on create and here is our database.
How many tables?
I'll start with the first table math underscore table number of columns seven.
And here we need to specify the columns of the table and their types.
The first column is id its type is integer.
And here I'll select I which is autoincrement and it's of type primary.
Because this will act as a primary key for our table.
Then the second one is the question.
It's of type string which is a varchar.
And I don't need to specify here anything.
Option one which is of type varchar.
The fourth column is option two which is of type varchar.
The fifth one is option three which is of type varchar option for Varchar, and the last one is the
correct underscore option varchar.
Then select save.
I need to specify a valid length, and here I need to specify 50 for the ID 200 for the question, 200
for the option one and the other options and the correct option click save.
And here we go.
This is our database.
Congratulations guys.
We installed Examp.
We created the database in phpMyAdmin.
And we're ready to fetch the data from this database into our Android application.