Welcome back.
We created our database my underscore quiz underscore db.
And we created the table math underscore table.
This math underscore table contains seven columns ID question option 123 and four.
And the correct option.
Now we can insert records.
So click on insert I'll select one.
This is the ID the question what is the result of five times six.
Specify the option one, 30, 35, 25 and 40 and specify the correct option, which is the 30, and
click go.
Click browse and you can see your database here and the Table Math table.
Select Math Table seven columns one record.
The first record is what is the result of five times six?
And these are the options and the correct option.
We need to fetch these questions from the math underscore table into Json response.
This is our mission.
So for that we need to use an API.
I'll create a new text document and I'll name it as my quiz API.
I want from you to focus with me.
An API application programming interface with a MySQL database refers to a set of rules, protocols,
and tools that allow external applications or systems to interact with and access data from a MySQL
database.
And in our case, we're going to use this API to access the MySQL database from Android application.
This enables developers to create, retrieve, update or delete data in the database without direct
access to the database.
Server APIs provide a structured way for applications to communicate with and manipulate the database,
which is particularly useful in web and mobile app development.
So I'm going to write codes here in my quiz API dot text in PHP language.
I want from you to focus with me.
It's very simple and very important.
I'll start with PHP, then I'll create con equals to my SQL underscore connect, and I'll specify localhost
root, empty string and my quiz underscore db.
In PHP, con is a variable holding the connection to the database.
So the dollar sign refers that this is a variable.
So con is a variable.
MySQL underscore connect.
This is a function used to create a connection to the MySQL database.
It takes four parameters the localhost the host name of the database server, and in this case it's
the local machine where the database is hosted.
Root the username used to connect to the database server.
An empty string.
This is where you would typically provide the password for the database user.
Since it's an empty string in your code, it suggests that you are using an empty password, which is
generally not recommended for production environments.
My quiz DB the name of the database you want to connect to.
So if we go back this is our database my underscore quiz underscore db.
And please guys make sure that you specify it correctly because it's case sensitive.
My underscore quiz underscore db.
This is how we specify and how to establish the connection to the database.
Then I'll specify another variable Stmt statement equals to connect prepare.
And here I need to specify the query.
Don't worry I'll specify and I'll lecture everything later on.
This is the valuable state equals to con.
Prepare, prepare.
This method prepares an SQL statement for execution.
In this code it's preparing a Select statement.
This is the statement.
Select the statement to retrieve data from the math underscore quiz table.
So this is the name of the table I'm using.
The select here is the SQL query and the SQL statement selects several columns from the math underscore
quiz table, including the question.
Option one.
Option two.
Option three.
Option four.
Correct underscore option from the math underscore quiz.
Make sure guys that you specify them exactly as the name of the columns, and otherwise it will create
an error.
So ID question option one, option two, option three, option four and correct underscore option.
After preparing the SQL statement, you can execute it and retrieve the result using additional MySQL
functions.
For example, you would use execute method to run the prepared statements and fetch the results.
So here I'll make a comment execute and here I'll start by stmt and call the execute function.
In the next video we'll continue with the API.