Welcome back.
We're going to use this API that we created before in order to get the data from database into Json
format.
So copy this PHP file, make sure that it is of extension PHP file.
Go to see.
Damp HD docs and create a new folder.
I'll name it as quiz, and inside this quiz folder I'll place my quiz API dot php file.
Make sure exam docs, quiz and my quiz API dot php.
Now turn on exam.
Click start start and then open Chrome.
Go to localhost.
And this is our dashboard.
And I'll remove this dashboard here and I'll add quiz.
This is the folder.
If we click enter we can see that this folder contains my quiz API dot php file.
If I click on it or add the extension.
My quiz API dot php.
PHP file click enter.
Then we have this error.
Don't worry, I'll show you how to solve the problems step by step.
Here we have uncaught Mysqli SQL exception.
No connection could be made because the target machine actively refuse it.
Since we didn't specify the port name.
Here we have port 4306.
I open the php file with notepad and here I need to specify the port name.
So whenever you encounter such an error, you need to specify the port name here 4306.
Make sure to save okay Ctrl S, then refresh and the error is changed to another error.
So the first error is solved.
There is another error table.
My quiz db dot math quiz doesn't exist.
Let me see here in the line six.
So in the select statement.
So go to the select Statement and Math underscore quiz.
Let's go to the database my quiz DB.
And here the table is called math underscore table and not math underscore quiz.
So here I need to change it to math underscore table.
Save it ctrl s then refresh.
And here we go.
There is another error undefined variable question array.
Maybe I missed something here in the question array on line 41.
Let me go to line 41.
And questions array okay.
You see I missed letter S Ctrl S to save then refresh.
And here we go.
This is our Json response.
You can see it starts with an array.
And then this is our first object question.
Option one.
Option two.
Option three option four and correct option.
Congratulations guys.
We fetch it the database data into Json response.
Again let's go to here and I'll add another row.
So I'll select math Table Insert.
And here I'll add the question.
And the correct answer is 81.
Click Go Browse and you can see this is the second question.
Then let's go back to here refresh.
And you can see it's a second Json object added here.
This is the first question.
You can see the comma and the second question.