Welcome back.
Till now, we succeeded in creating our own API and transforming and converting the database data and
records into Json response.
Now let's move to the next step which is retrofit.
And since we're going to follow the mVVM architecture in this application, I'll start from the section
which is removed.
Data source and retrofit configurations in Android.
Development.
Retrofit is a popular library for making network requests to a Rest API representational State Transfer
Application programming interface.
It simplifies the process of sending and receiving data from a web service.
When working with retrofit, you'll often come across concepts like data classes, retrofit instances,
and API service interface.
Let's start with the data classes or Pojo.
Plain old Java objects.
When working with retrofit data, classes are commonly used to represent the structure of the data you
expect to send or receive from a web service.
You would use data classes or modal classes to represent the structure of the data you want to send
as the request body, or the data you expect to receive as the response from the API.
As mentioned in the previous section, we can use online tools to transform our Json response into Pojo
classes, or we can do it manually.
The second part, or the second step is to create the API service interface.
In retrofit, an API or service interface is a simple interface that defines the endpoints Http methods
like get, post, put, delete, and the structure of the network requests to a rest API.
Each method in the interface represents a specific API endpoint, and retrofit will generate the necessary
code to handle the network request and response processing.
The third part is the retrofit instance.
A retrofit instance is the entry point to using the retrofit library.
It's responsible for configuring the settings that apply to all your network requests, such as the
base URL of the API, converters for parsing responses, and Http client settings.
These are the parts of retrofit.
Now let's start with the data classes, then move to the service interface and the retrofit instance.