Welcome back.
Let's start creating our modal classes.
Open Android Studio and create a new project named as the Quiz App.
Then inside this package I'll create a new package named as modal.
And inside this modal I'll create the modal classes for our application.
I'll close all of these classes and in order to create the modal classes, you should refer to the Json
response here.
If we look closer we have an array.
And these objects the first object separated by comma and the second object.
I'll copy this whole response and I'll use an online tool called Json to Pojo.
Then I need to choose the package name here.
The package is Campmaster coding.
Dot the quiz app and paste it here and the class name.
I'll name it as question, then select Json.
Select Json because I'm going to use this Json converter.
And here I'll click on preview.
And this is our class.
Copy it.
And I'm going to create a new Java class.
I'll name it as question and I'll paste the whole response.
I'll copy this copy to clipboard.
Then I'll paste this.
Okay.
Remove this.
And we need to add the dependency.
So let's go to the Gradle build.gradle.
And let's add the dependencies for retrofit and the libraries that we'll use in this application.
Since I'm going to use mVVM architecture I need to add the lifecycle ViewModel and LiveData dependencies.
So for that go to Developer.android.com slash jetpack slash Android slash releases slash lifecycle.
Then you scroll down to get the dependencies.
Select Kotlin and here I'll copy this lifecycle version.
Paste it here and I need to use the ViewModel.
This is the ViewModel.
And I need to use the live data.
So copy live data.
And if you notice there is x, you can remove it because this is for Kotlin.
Later on when we move to the Kotlin section, we'll use the dash.
Or you can simply scroll down to select Java here the Java codes and select the view model and the live
data.
So I'll copy them and val lifecycle okay.
This is for Java because we're working with Java.
The second library that we're going to use is the retrofit.
This is our friend.
So go to square dot Github.io slash retrofit and click on download.
And here I need to get this dependency copy.
And here I'll use retrofit.
Then I need to get the latest version.
To get it I'll go to view GitHub project and select down to 92.9.0.
Here I'll put it like this.
And don't miss to add and change this dependency into this syntax.
I need a converter.
So back to our retrofit.
I'll go up and I'll use Json copy it implementation retrofit converter Json and 2.9.0.
Make sure that you get the same version for the converter and the retrofit 2.9.0 sink.
Now later on we'll talk about these retrofit converters.
Close it and you can see the problems are solved.
We created question option one, option two, option three, option four and correct option variables.
These six strings represent our modal class, our data that is fetched from the database into our application.
I'll remove this and annotation here.
I'll add dot modal class okay in order to solve because I'm going to place it or I place it.
The question inside the modal.