We added the dependency of Json converter library.
But why we need this converter?
The Json converter is a component of retrofit.
It's responsible for converting Json data from the network response into Kotlin or Java objects, and
vice versa in retrofit.
You typically configure the Json converter as part of your retrofit instance.
So Json converter used to convert Java objects into their Json representation.
It can also be used to convert a Json string to an equivalent Java object.
Think about Json converters used for serialization and deserialization of Json response.
Json provides several built in Serializers and Deserializers as serializer allows to convert a Json
string to corresponding Java type, a Deserializer allows to convert from Java to Json representation.
We're going to serialize at first, because we need to get the response from the Json into Kotlin or
Java objects.
Back to our question model class.
We use this annotation serialized name and this annotation expose.
At first, let me discuss the serialized name and serialized name.
Annotation is an annotation provided by the Json library.
It's used to map Java or Kotlin objects fields to the key or field names in Json data.
When you receive Json data from an API like this response, the keys in the Json may not always match
the variable names you want to use in your Java class.
So for example, here we have the string question.
If I name it as question body.
For example, this is the variable question body.
This question body is not matching the key question.
So at serialized name annotation allows you to specify the mapping between the Json key and the objects
field.
Here I'm telling this question body is similar to the question key in the API response.
My advice to you is to create the same variable name as the keys and as the columns in the database.
So here we have the key question option one, option two, option three, option four, and correct
underscore option for that.
In order to prevent any possible error, just use the same variable names as the key names.
Question is similar to question option one is similar to option one and so on.
Here I want from you to focus correct underscore option is different from correct option.
So add serialized name should be annotation should be added.
For example if we look at option four it's similar to option for key here.
So option four I can get rid of serialized name annotation.
So I can remove serialized name because option four is matching option for key in the Json response,
but the correct option is not matching correct option here in the key.
So I need to add at serialized name annotation, and I'll specify the correct option inside the serialized
name annotation.
Here I'm referencing.
This correct option is linked and mapping this correct option variable to this key.
Correct underscore option key.
Again guys, whenever you have similar variables, there is no need to use at serialized name.
But for better implementation and to provide any possible error, please keep the serialized name and
notation.
Now let's move to add, expose and notation.
Add, expose and notation is also a Json annotation, but it's used for controlling field serialization
and deserialization behavior by default.
Jason, Serializes and Deserializes all fields of a class, but if you want to exclude specific fields
from serialization or deserialization, you can use Add expose annotation.
To use Add expose annotation, you need to configure your Json instance to honor it, and you do it
by creating a Json instance with a Json builder and configuring it to exclude fields annotated with
expose.
So I can use dot exclude fields without expose annotation method in the Json builder, but I'll not
use it in this application just to inform you and to tell you about the add serialized name annotation
and add Expose annotation so you can exclude them from deserialization or serialization.
We learned about this Json converter.
We learned about expose annotation and serialized name.
Now let's move to create other retrofit parts.