Back to our Json response.
If we look closer, we have this square bracket.
So our response starts with the square bracket indicating that the whole response is an array Json array.
And inside this array we have this first object, and this is the second Json object separated by the
comma.
We can't directly serialize and deserialize this Json object using this question class, because this
question class has six fields and these are indicating the object.
This.
But this object is nested from the array.
So the solution for this problem is to create another modal class.
So inside this modal package I'll create a new Java class and I'll name it as question list.
This is an empty class.
I'll extend it from array list because we have a nested objects inside this array, because our response
starts with this array, and there is no key for this array.
So I can directly use this empty class.
It's of type question import the array list class.
And here we go.
This is our second modal class called question list.
It's an empty class just to get the response and include this response.
Because the response the API response and the Json response start with this square bracket.
No key or value is directly a value of an array.
Back to the retrofit steps.
We added the data classes.
Now let's move to create the API service interface.
We need to create an interface to define our different methods that will be used for network transactions.
I'll create a new package, I'll name it as retrofit.
And inside this retrofit package I'll create a new interface and I'll name it as questions API.
A retrofit API service interface is an essential component used to define the structure and behavior
of network requests to a RESTful API.
This interface acts as a contract, as a bridge between your Android application and the web service,
specifying the available API endpoints and the expected response format.
The retrofit then uses this interface to create the necessary implementation for making network requests.
Each method inside this interface should specify the Http request method either get, post, put, delete,
and the endpoint URL relative to the base URL, and any required query parameters, request bodies,
or headers.
You can also specify the expected response form.
In this example, I'll use apt get.
Again, guys, I want from you to focus with me and please refer to the previous sections and especially
the mVVM plus retrofit in order to understand all these Http requests and responses.
And also I clarified them in very deep detail.
So please go back to the mVVM plus retrofit section and get details about these terms.
But don't worry, I'll clarify everything.
I write the annotation get specify the Http method and the relevant parts of the URL.
Here I need to define the endpoint.
So if we go back to the response the endpoint.
Here is my quiz API dot php.
So I'll copy it and I'll paste it here.
This is the end point.
Then I'll use coal and the retrofit to.
And here I need to specify questions list question list.
It's a class that we created before and I'll name the method get questions.
In retrofit, the coal class is used to wrap a network request and represents the result of an asynchronous
operation.
The generic type question list represents the expected response type, and I am expecting this response
from the API starting with this square bracket, which is a Json array.
This is the name of the method get questions.
So it's returning type is call of questions list.
When calling this method get questions, it will send a network request and expect to receive a response
of type question list.
And this question list acts as a structure of the response data you expect from the API.
And as said before.
For we are expecting an array without a key value pairs.
It's directly an array of Json response.
So for that we use this empty class that extends from array list of quests.
So here I'm expecting to get a question list structure.
Again.
This method get questions is defined to send a network request to a specific API endpoint, which is
my quiz API dot PHP and expects a response in the form of a call containing the question list.