Welcome back.
We've done with the remote data source and the repository.
So we finished the model layer.
Now let's move to the view model layer.
The view model is a crucial component responsible for managing and providing data to the UI, the view
while maintaining the separation of concerns.
It's part of Android architecture components and serves as a bridge between the data source, the model
and the UI components.
The view.
The primary purpose of a view model is to store and manage UI related data, ensuring that this data
persists across configuration changes like, for example, device rotation and that the UI remains responsive.
Let's move to Android Studio and learn how to add and create the view models.
I'll create a new package, I'll name it as View Model and make sure that you name your packages with
small letters.
Then inside this package I'll create a new Java class and I'll name it as Quiz View Model.
Again, guys, I want from you to focus with me.
There are a lot of concepts, a lot of details.
Please go back to the View model section in order to learn more about View models.
But don't worry, I'll explain.
Everything I write extends the view model.
We have two types of view models either Android View model or View model, and they are both from the
life cycle package.
Both the view model and Android View model are components provided by the Android architecture, components
that play a role in managing and persisting UI related data across configuration changes.
However, they serve slightly different purposes and have different life cycles.
For example, the regular view model is a component of the Android architecture components and is part
of the mVVM model view ViewModel pattern.
It's a basic class for a view models, and it's not tied to the Android framework.
This is the view model.
It's an abstract class.
It's designed to store and manage UI related data, and provides an abstraction layer between the UI
components, activities, and fragments and the underlying data source.
For example, a database, network, service or repository.
This separation of concerns helps in maintaining a clean and testable architecture, but a view model
is not aware of Android application or context, and should not be used to access Android specific components
like system, services, resources or preferences.
It makes the management of pure data and presentation logic very simple.
While the Android View model is a subclass of a view model that is aware of the Android application
context.
This allows you to access Android specific components such as system services, resources, and preferences,
making it suitable for situations where you need application wide context or access to system services.
In this example, I'm not going to access context, so I remove Android.
I'll use view model.
I don't need to access the context.
Okay, I'll start by creating a quiz repository.
Instance repository equals to new quiz repository.
The repository is used to interact with data source example an API in this application and fetch data.
Then I need to create live data of type questions.
List questions.
Live data.
Live data is an observable data holder class that allows you to observe changes in the underlying data.
In this case, it's expected to hold the question list object, which suggests that it's intended to
store a list of questions.
Then I'll create a constructor empty constructor for the quiz view model, and inside it I'll initialize
the questions list.
Live data repository dot get questions from API.
This method used to fetch questions from an API.
It's likely returns a live data object containing a question list object.
So if we go back you can see from the repository it's returning type is live data of question list.
Then I need to create a method called get question list or questions list live data or I can create
it.
It's a getter method.
For this live data you can click Alt Plus Insert Getter and select this or you can write it.
This is a getter method that allows.
External components.
Example the UI components to access the questions list.
Live data it returns questions list.
Live data as a live data of type.
Questions list object.
Congratulations, we finished the view model.