Welcome back.
Now let's move to the main activity.
And here I'll create activity main binding object called binding and a quiz ViewModel object and a list
of question.
I name it as question list.
Then I'll create a static variables result and total questions in order to store the result in these
variables, static and result equals to zero and static in total questions equals to zero and I equals
to zero.
Let's move to the Oncreate method.
Initialize these variables.
Here I'm using data binding util.
This is the data binding setting.
The result equals to zero.
Here I am resetting the scores and the total questions equals to zero.
Now we need to create an instance of quiz view model.
I'll start with the quiz view model.
Object equals to new view model provider.
And passing this dot get.
What is the view model.
It's quiz view model.
So here I need to specify view model dot class.
This is a common way to obtain a view model instance in an activity or fragment.
Let's break it down to understand quiz view model.
This is the variable that holds the instance of the quiz view model, new view model provider and passing
this which is the owner is a class provided by Android View model architecture components.
It's used to create and manage view model instances.
When you create a view model provider instance, you typically pass activity or fragment as a parameter
and this refers to the current activity or fragment.
And since we are working with the main activity, so this refers to the main activity.
Get retrieves an instance of quiz view model class.
The view model provider is responsible for ensuring that you get the same view model instance associated
with the same activity or fragment across configuration changes.
Example.
The screen rotation.
The purpose of this code is to create or retrieve a quiz view model instance, which allows you to work
with data related to your quiz feature in a lifecycle aware manner.
I want from you to focus now.
When the app launches, we need to display the first question and then load the other questions.
When the user clicks on the next button.
So for that, we need to display two things the first question and the next question.
So for that I'll create a method here to display the first question.
It's called display.
First question I'll start by quiz view model dot get question list live data I'm calling this view model
and calling this get question list live data method.
Because I'm going to observe the first question.
In this case I'm observing live data from a view model.
And here I'll use dot observe method.
I'll pass this as a first parameter, which is the owner and the owner of this activity.
And the new observer and I am overriding on changed method.
Dot observe method is used to observe a changes in the live data.
The first argument.
This represents the life cycle owner, typically an activity or fragment, and in this case it's a main
activity.
The second argument is a new observer that defines what to do when the data inside the live data changes
unchanged.
Method.
This method is part of the observer interface.
It's called when the data inside the live data changes in this specific code, it receives a questions
list object as an argument.
When the data changes, we need to get the new data from this question list variable.
So the first thing I need to do is to assign the question list that I created here equals to the questions
that it is passed for the updated data.
So this is the new updated data.
So I need to update the list question list with these new data.
Then I'll use data binding to update the relative text view.
And the other for radio buttons.
So for that I'll use binding dot text question.
This is how we access the views inside the binding.
The text question refers to this text view.
You can see this is the ID dot set text.
And here I need to get the question number one which is at index zero.
So this is how we get a question from a question list from an array list get question okay.
This is the first question.
Now we need to set the four options.
So in the same way binding dot radio one dot set text to question dot get at index zero dot get option
one.
And the same way I'll do for the other three radio buttons.
Save the project and I'll call this display first question here and run the application.
And I have this error.
The maximum recommended compile SDK is 33.
So I'd go to the manifest here the target API.
I change it to 34, go to Build.gradle, change it to 34 and the compile SDK 34.
Sync.
Now run again and this is our application.
It's not fetching the first question.
So I need to run exam ensure that it is functioning good.
So I need to start Apache MySQL.
And then I need to add the internet permission.
And I think that we provide the wrong IP address.
So let's go back to the questions API or the retrofit instance.
Here I need to specify the correct IP address.
In the next video we'll learn about the network security rules because we're working with the local
host.