We tried to get the first question.
Everything is working fine.
The layout, the activity, the architecture, but nothing happened.
We need to specify the security rules.
So the problem here is a security issue.
I'll create a new file in the XML.
So open XML and create new XML resource file.
And I'll name it as network underscore security underscore config.
Go split mode and I'll change this preference screen to network dash security dash config.
Here I remove this namespace.
And this file is used to define network security configurations for your app.
It's important to use this configuration file to enhance the security and protect sensitive data during
network communication.
For example, you can require that all network traffic should use Https, SSL, TLS to encrypt data
in transit, preventing man in the middle attacks and data leaks.
The default behavior of Android is to disallow clear text unencrypted network traffic for security reasons.
However, in some cases your app might need to connect to non Https servers, and in such scenarios
you can explicitly allow clear text traffic using this file.
This is done by setting clear text traffic permitted to true.
So I'll start by using base config.
And by the way, I'll show you another way to do this.
Clear text traffic permitted equals to true.
And inside this base traffic base config I'll use trust anchors and certificates.
You can specify the trust anchors or certificates that your app trusts.
This helps in ensuring that your app communicates only with trusted servers and validates the authenticity
of the server's certificate.
This is crucial for protecting against man in the middle attacks.
Then here in the application I need to specify network security config and I'll use this example and
network security configuration file that we created now.
So here I'm referencing this file.
And I'm telling Android that the network security config is specified in this file.
Or if you don't need to create this file you can specify users clear traffic or text traffic to.
True.
It's very simple.
Okay guys.
So you can use either this method or this method network security config.
Let's run our application.
And again we don't have any response.
And to solve this error we didn't get anything.
Now we are going to change the address the base URL.
If we go back to the localhost and the API we can see that 127.00.0.1 is used here.
I can't use 127.0.0.1 because it refers to the host, but in emulators I need to use this IP address
10.00 .2.2.
This is a special IP address that is used as a loopback address to access the host machine's localhost
from within an Android emulator.
It's a convenient way to access web services or resources running on the host machine while testing
your Android application on an emulator.
When you use 10.0 .2.2 in your Android applications, code as the host for network requests, or when
configuring your app to connect to a server.
As this, the emulator redirects the traffic to the host machine's loopback interface.
This allows the emulator to communicate with services running on the host.
Now let's run our application and here we go.
This is question number one.
What is the result of five times six, 30, 35, 25 and 40?
Back to the response we can see.
The first question is this.
And congratulations guys.
We succeeded in getting the first question.
Now let's move to get all the questions.