Welcome back.
We succeeded in getting and displaying the first question.
Now we need to display the other questions and the next questions when the user clicks on the next button.
By the way, where is the next button?
This is a layout issue.
I need to configure this text view and make the layout margin to 100.
Run it again and you can see the next button appears.
I need to add some margins here to that.
The to this text view.
And I'll add eight margin left and margin right eight run.
And here we go.
Now let's move to the main activity and create a new method called display.
All or next questions here I need to trigger this function when the user clicks on the next button.
So binding dot next button next dot set on click listener new view on click listener use display next
question inside this display.
Next question here I'll direct check the user if he finishes the questions and the quiz.
So I'm going to direct him to the results activity I'll configure this later on.
Now let's focus on displaying the question and getting the correct option.
I need to use a selected option integer value to check the selected option.
If it is not equal to minus one and it's not null.
Okay.
Binding dot radio group dot get checked radio button ID here I'm getting from the four radio buttons
the ID of the selected option.
I'm checking if this selected option doesn't equal minus one, so the user makes a selection radio button.
Radio button equals to find the view by ID, because I'm going to use this to detect the selected option
I'm casting it to this selected option.
Now if there is a next question then we need to do an if condition.
So if question list dot size minus I which is the the current question greater than zero.
What we need to do.
We need to get the total number of questions and check if the chosen option is correct.
Here I need to start with the getting number of questions.
So total questions equal to questions list dot size method.
This is very simple.
I use an array list question list and getting the size of it.
Then I'm getting to check if the chosen option is correct.
If radio button dot get text dot to string equals to.
Here I'm checking questions list dot get at index I dot get correct option if it is correct.
If the user chooses the correct option, I need to increase the result variable by one and set the text
this text to correct to correct answer binding dot text question or text result dot set text to correct
answer and the correct answers okay, this is if the chosen option is correct, so the user selects
the correct answer.
If I equals to zero, then I plus plus.
If it is the first question, increase I by one.
Now I need to display the next question.
So binding dot text question dot set text to question number I get the number by I plus one.
And here I need to use the question list dot get I not zero.
If we go back to the display first question we did it by getting the first index which is zero.
Here I'm getting the index I.
So I refers to the question index dot get question.
Then I need to update the radio buttons, the four radio buttons and display the four options.
So radio one dot set text to questions list dot get I dot get option one and also similar to the next
options.
And I want from you to focus with me and think like me.
We need to check if it is the last question, so we need to change that button from next to finish.
So if I which refers to the question index question list dot size and comparing it with the size of
the array list that contains the questions.
So if the index of the question equals to the question list dot size minus one, this is the last question
in the array list.
I'm going to use binding dot button.
Next dot set text.
To finish.
Here I'm changing the button title from next to finish.
Then I'm going to use binding dot radio group dot clear check.
Because I'm going to move to another question.
I need to clear the selection of the previous one and increase the I index, which is the question index
by one.
This is in the if close.
This is the if selected option is not null.
Else we need to check or display a toast message telling the user to make a selection.
So if the user didn't select any option and it clicks on the next button, I need to display a toast
message telling him that you need to make a selection.
Here.
I need to check also and use else condition.
And here this else is for this.
More questions to display.
I scroll down and remove this else and paste it here.
Then if radio button dot get text dot to string equals to question list dot get I minus one dot get
correct option.
Then we need to display the text text result dot set text to correct answer and we display the result
variable.
Also, I need to increase result by one.
Let's run and test our next button.
This is question number one.
Select 30 next.
So the correct answer is one.
Question number two what is the result of nine times nine.
And congratulation.
This is the second question.
So we are fetching all the questions here.
What is the result of nine times nine for example 80 to finish.
You can see finish is displayed and not next.
In the next videos we're going to direct the user to the results activity.