When the user finishes the quiz, we need to direct him when he clicks on the finish button to the results
activity.
In this video, we'll create this results activity.
Open comm Cadinot the quiz app.
And here I'll create a new activity empty views activity and I'll name it as results Activity.
Click finish.
Let's go to the layout file.
Go to split mode and in this activity I'll include two text views and one.
But of course I'll create a drawable.
So I'll copy this gradient back and name it as back to.
And I'll change these colors to these colors.
Go back to the activity results and I'll use the background and drawable gradient to okay.
As I told you, this activity will contain two text views and one button.
And by the way this will use the layout tag because I'm using data binding.
So.
Inside this constraint layout, I'll start creating the text views and the button.
And congratulations, we created our layout.
It's very simple.
Two text views and one button.
Now let's move to the results activity.
Inside it I'll create the binding activity result binding binding.
And here I'll use binding equals to data binding util dot Setcontentview.
This dot layout dot activity results I'm using this data binding and binding dot text answer dot set
text.
Your score is.
I'm going to get the score from the main activity dot result variable which is the static the total
number of questions.
So the result is five answers over ten questions.
So five over ten.
This is the algorithm.
We have two variables the result and the total question.
Then I'll use the binding dot button back dot set on click listener new view on click listener.
And here I need to direct the user from this activity to the main activity.
Okay.
Save the project.
And I want to make one last thing.
Here in the main activity, when the user finishes the quiz, I need to direct the user to the results
activity.
So I'll check the title or the name of the button if it is equal to the finish.
If binding dot button next dot get text.
If it is equal to finish then I need to direct the user to the results activity.
It's very simple.
Let's run our application.
This is question number one.
Next what is the result of nine times nine I select 83.
Click finish and you are directed to the results activity.
Your score is one over two.
This is the correct answer.
And this is the total questions variable.
Back to quiz and you are directed again to the quiz.
Congratulations guys.
We finished this amazing application.
We reviewed the retrofit mVVM architecture and we introduced a new concept which is the MySQL databases
and phpMyAdmin.