Hello, my friends, and welcome back.
In this video, we'll start building our contacts manager application.
We'll follow the Mvvm design pattern with room database.
So in our local data source, the room database, I'll start designing the entity SQLite, which is
the database and the Dao and the contacts Manager Application room database contains only one table,
which is the entity named as contacts, table or contacts in this entity.
This table I have three columns contact id, which is of type int contact name, which is of type string
and the contact email which is of type string.
Let's jump into Android studio and start creating our database.
And the first step in creating our database is to start with the entity class.
To use the room database, we need to add its dependency from the Developer.android.com website.
So scroll down, search for Android X room or go to this link developer.android.com slash jetpack slash
android slash releases slash room and copy this dependency.
These are optional and if you are using the Capt or KSP Kotlin symbol processing, you can use these.
I created a new project called Contacts Manager Application in Android Studio and go to build.gradle
and paste this dependency the room database Click sync now and I need the annotation processor because
all operations like insert, delete, update and et-cetera are annotated also there.
As mentioned before, the Add entity Dao database annotations are included, so I need to use the annotation
processor.
And the annotation processor is a tool that processes annotations at compile time to generate code and
perform other tasks.
It's often used to automate repetitive code generation and to enforce specific behaviors in your code
base.
So these annotations provide additional information to the compiler or tools about how to handle the
marked elements.
For example, in Android you might use annotations like Override, suppress length or custom annotations
that you define.
Let's start with the first step by creating a new Java class and I'll name it as contacts and to tell
Android studio that this class will act as an entity class in our room database.
I'll annotated with entity annotation.
An entity is a fundamental component that represents a table in the SQLite database.
Each entity class corresponds to one table and the fields properties or the variables within the entity
class represent INT columns in that table.
Entities define the structure and the schema of your database tables.
As mentioned before, I have only one entity class called contacts, and I have inside this table three
columns, contact ID, contact name and contact email one of type int and two of type strings.
And by the way, you can specify various attributes within the entity annotation such as the table name,
primary keys and indices.
So for example, I'll name this entity or this table table name equal to contacts underscore table.
You can specify it like contacts or name it whatever you want.
If you don't specify the table name here in the entity, the name of the table is specified exactly
as the name of the class.
If I remove this table, name the table in our database, but I prefer specifying the table name and
I'll name it as contacts underscore table.
So now I created this table, this empty table, no columns.
I name it as contacts table.
The fields within the entity class represent columns in the database table.
In this example we have ID name and email fields corresponding to columns in the users table or the
contacts underscore table.
So for that I'll create private int id, private string name and private string email.
Three fields represent three columns in my contacts.
Underscore table the name of Collins till now our ID name and email.
If I need to change the name of the column you can use at column info.
The column info annotation is used.
To specify additional details about how a field, property or variable in an entity class maps to a
column in the database table.
This annotation provides control over column specific properties and behaviors.
You can use column info annotation to explicitly specify the name of the database column that corresponds
to a field in your entity.
For example, this ID if I need to create a database table with the first column contact underscore
ID, I can create a field without a column ID like this contact underscore ID and the room database
will create a column named as contact ID, or I can specify here the ID as a variable and the column
info and I'll specify the name property equal to contacts.
Underscore ID.
The name of the column will be contact, underscore ID and not ID here.
The name of the column is name.
I can change it using the same way the column info name equal to contact underscore name.
I'm just showing you the power of using the annotations in room and in Android column info.
Again guys, you can skip this column info annotation so the room database will create columns using
the name of the variable you create in all tables.
We need to specify a primary key using a unique and primary key that it will not be repetitive and in
this case the contact underscore ID will act as a primary key.
So here in the ID field, I'll use an annotation called Primary Key and I'll specify autogenerate equal
to true.
The primary key annotation indicates that the ID field is the primary key for this table.
The autogenerate equal to true attribute means that the SQL will automatically assign unique IDs to
the new records.
I'll create the constructors Alt+ insert.
One having all fields and one having nothing.
And this is used to prevent any null pointer exception.
I'll create getters and setters.
For all elements.