The second step in creating our database is to create the Dao.
Dao stands for Data Access Object, and it's a critical component of the room database library in Android.
The IO is an interface that defines a set of methods for performing database operations on entities
database tables.
A Dao is an interface annotated with at Dao annotation.
So let's go to Android studio and build this Dao.
I'll create a new Java class select interface and I'll name it as contact Dao and I'll annotate it with
the a o.
A Dao is an interface annotated with Dao annotation.
It specifies a contract for interacting with the database, including methods for inserting, updating,
deleting or querying data.
I'll start by creating the first method void insert and I need to insert a contact object of type contacts.
So I need to pass contacts and I name it as contact.
This method is responsible for inserting data into a database table and I'll annotate it with insert
annotation and this annotation marks a method.
As an insert operation, I can create other annotations.
Update, delete and query.
I'll create another method called delete and I need to delete a specific contact.
So for that I need to specify the contact object and I'll mark it as delete with the delete annotation
to mark a method as a delete operation, you can define custom SQL queries within the Dao methods using
the Add query annotation.
So add query annotation and here you need to specify the SQL query.
This allows you to execute complex database operations while still benefiting from rooms type safety
and the query annotation allows you to define custom SQL queries and map the results to Java or Kotlin
objects.
So for that I need to create a method called Get all contacts.
And this method returning type should be a list of contact objects.
So list of contact objects that we have created before alt plus enter to import the class of the list
from Java util and here I need to specify the SQL query in this annotation I need to use select which
is an SQL query all from and I need to specify the name of the table.
If I go to the contacts here, the table name is contacts table, I'll copy it because it's a case sensitive
and paste it here.
So select all, get all contacts from the contacts table.
This is how we create custom queries, how to delete and and insert new contacts into our database using
the contact Dao By using the OS in room, you can interact with your database in a structured and efficient
manner while also benefiting from room's features like type, safety thread, safety and automatic query
generation.