Hello, my friends, and welcome back.
In this video, we'll learn about repository.
We succeeded in creating our room database.
The next step is to create the repository.
A repository in Mvvm architecture is an intermediary layer between the ViewModel and the data sources,
such as a database or network service.
It abstracts the details of data retrieval and provides a clean API for the ViewModel to interact with.
It's mainly used to manage multiple resources of data.
The repository can gather data from different data sources, different rest APIs, cache local database
storage and it provides this data to the rest of the app.
This is the function of the repository and the main purpose of creating the repository to gather data
from different data sources, rest APIs, cache local database storage and providing this data to the
rest of the app.
When you have only one source of your data, such as our application, the room database, you don't
need to create repository, but for demonstrating the usage and the main role of repository, I'll use
it in our application.
I'll create a new Java class and I'll name it as my repository or repository.
We search for the available data sources and in our application we have only the room database, the
offline database.
So for that I'll create private final contact Dao and I'll use and I name it as contact Dao object.
So when dealing with room databases, you need to deal with the contact dao in the repository.
Alt+ enter to create the constructor.
Having this contact dao as a parameter and initializing.
Okay, so this is our repository.
Now.
This repository encapsulates data access and retrieval logic.
It receives a contact Dao object in its constructor, which provides access to the local database,
assuming you are using room.
And this is what we've done and every method created in the Dao, you should mention it here in the
repository.
So I have three methods insert, delete and get all contacts I need to to use these methods from the
For that.
I'll start with the first method.
Add contact.
It receives a contact object and I need to call this method insert in the Dao.
So I'll use this contact dao object dot insert.
And here I need to pass this parameter as a parameter inside this insert method.
It's just managing all the methods in the different data sources.
Again, if you have only one data source, you don't need to use the repository.
Publicvoid delete contact receives a contact object and execute the contact Dao dot delete method and
passing the contact as the argument for this delete method.
The last step is the get all contacts and it's returning type is a list of contacts.
So for that I need to create here public list of contacts object.
Get all contacts and I need to call the contact Dao dot get all contacts Alt+ enter to import the class
of the list and here I need to use the return statement.
So these are three methods are listed in the repository that are similar to the Dao.
If you have any source of data, you need to mention all the methods here in the repository.