Room database operations such as insertions, updates and queries should not be executed on the main
UI thread because they can potentially block the UI causing the app to become unresponsive.
We need to offload these database operations to background threads.
By doing this, you keep the UI thread free to handle user interactions and ensure that your app remains
responsive.
When we move to the Kotlin sections, we will use the coroutines that will do these operations in the
background.
But in Java we need to use handler and executer service in order to execute the methods in the background.
So I can't write like this.
Add contact and call the contact Dao insert method directly because this will be executed in the main
UI thread making problems for our application and cause A and R application not responding or maybe
crashes.
So to prevent any possible error we need to use handlers and the executer services in order to do this
job or this operation.
In the background I'll use executer service, I'll name it as executor and alt+ enter to import this
class equals to executer dot new single thread executer and executer service.
Usually a thread pool executor is used to offload these database operations to background threads.
By doing this, you keep the UI thread free to handle user interactions and ensure that your app remains
responsive as single threaded executer is created, meaning that database operation will be executed
sequentially in a background thread.
This can help avoid concurrency issues when dealing with database access.
Then the second step is to use the handler Alt+ enter to import the handler and make sure that you use
the handler from the OS package equal to new handler.
And here I need to use the looper dot, get main looper.
Why we use handlers while database operations occur in the background, you often need to update the
UI with the results of these operations.
However, UI updates must be performed on the main UI thread to avoid view related issues.
The handler with Looper dot get main Looper method is used to post tasks to the main UI threads messages
queue.
This ensures that any UI related code such as updating text views or recycler views is executed on the
main thread.
So we need to execute the add context in the background.
So I use the executor service.
I need to update the UI, the text views or the recycler view.
So for that I use the handler with Looper by combining an executor service with the handler.
This is for background database operations and handler for UI updates.
You achieve many benefits such as thread separation synchronization and responsive UI thread separation
background Database operations are separated from UI updates, preventing UI blocking and an application
not responding errors.
Synchronization.
Concurrent access to the database is managed by executer service, ensuring that database operations
occur sequentially and avoiding race condition.
Responsive UI updates are performed on the main thread using the handler, ensuring a responsive user
interface.
I need to use the executor to execute this method in the background and I'll use the handler to update
the UI.
So for that I need to use the executor dot execute method.
And here I need to use a new runnable and you can see I override it.
The run method.
I need to move this method here into the run.
Method Runnable is an interface that defines a task to be executed.
Typically on a separate thread.
It represents a unit of work that can be executed as synchronously.
Runnable objects are commonly used with thread related APIs, including executer service to perform
background tasks, and the runnable interface defines a single method void run that is executed when
the runnable task is.
Executed.
Runnable objects are used to encapsulate code that you want to run asynchronously on a separate thread
By submitting a runnable to an executor service, you delegate the execution of that task to the thread
managed by the executor.
So in order to execute this code in the background, we need to create an executor which is used for
background database operations, executor service.
Then we need to use the handler for used for the updating the UI and linking this executor with runnable
is used to provide the run method that will execute this code asynchronously on separate thread.
So this is how in Java we perform background tasks.
I'll do with the same with the other methods.
Delete and get contacts and I'll move this code and here I need to initialize it in the repository constructor
and I'll make it as public in order to use it in the other methods and prevent the duplication of codes.
So here executor and I need to cut this handler and handler.
Okay, this is from the repository constructor and I'll use the executor in the other methods such as
delete contact.
So here, executor, I need to provide new runnable and inside the run I need to move this method and
execute it in the background.