If we look at the run method of the runnable, we can see that the returning type is void.
This means that it will return nothing.
If we go to get all contacts method.
We can't execute this in the background because at first the run will not return anything and I need
to return a list of contacts object.
And the second reason is that I need to publish contacts to get all contacts and publish it to the UI.
So this is will be executed in the background and the add contact contact.
The insert method will be executed on a separate thread and in the background.
But this I need to be executed and published the UI with the new contacts received from the database.
So for that I'll use the live data.
Live data is often used in both the repository and the Dao to facilitate the observation of database
changes and provide real time updates to the UI.
The first step is to go to the Dao and I need to update this list.
I'll encapsulate this list inside the live data object of type list of contacts objects.
Import the class of the live data.
When you have methods that are annotated with query and you are going to display something using the
select operator in SQL.
Always use the live data by returning data as live data.
The room library ensures that the data is observed by the repository or ViewModel allowing for real
time updates when the underlying data changes.
And if you have any trouble in the live data import from the lifecycle, you can import the dependency
for it.
By using this live data implement station and the live or the view model here.
So I'll copy this implementation for the ViewModel and the live data.
In the next video we'll talk about ViewModel so I can import it here.
Latest versions of Android X, The life cycle is included.
So as you can see, I imported Android X dot lifecycle dot live data without any problem and usage of
this dependency.
Also the live data and I need to use the lifecycle version variable sync now so I can use ViewModel
and the live data in my application.
If I have any problem, just add the dependency.
If we go to the repository now, I need to change the returning type of this method to live data object.
This is the type of the live data and this is the type of the list in the repository.
Live data is typically used to expose data from the room database to the ViewModel and ultimately to
the UI components, activities or fragments.
The repository interacts with the room database to retrieve data and it wraps the data in a live data
object before passing it to the ViewModel.
By using the live data, the repository ensures that the data can be observed by the ViewModel, and
any changes in the underlying data are automatically reflected in the UI without the need to for explicit
updates.
And one last step in the repository is to change this parameter.
Pass an application alt+ enter.
And here I need to initialize the context database so contacts database equal to course or contacts
database dot get instance.
And here I need to pass the context which is the application in this case.
And this contact dao this dot contact dao equal to contact database dot get contact Dao.
This is how we initialize the database in the repository and how to initialize the Dao in the repository
and execute the methods and the background threads.