We created the room database and the repository.
In this video, we'll create the view model.
The purpose of the view model is to acquire and keep the information that is necessary for an activity
or a fragment.
It acts as a link between the model and the view.
It's responsible for transforming the data from the model.
It provides data streams to the view.
The activity or the fragment should be able to observe changes in the view model.
View models usually expose this information via live data or Android data binding.
Let's jump into Android studio and create our view model.
Create a new Java class and I'll name it as my view model.
And typically we need to extend the view model from Android lifecycle.
But if we open the repository, I need to initialize this repository and to initialize it I need to
call its constructor and pass an application as a parameter.
If you need to use the context inside your view model, you should use Android View model AVM instead
of a view model because it contains the application context.
I'll show you the problem here.
I need to initialize and create an instance from the repository, my repository and in the constructor
of this view model I need to initialize it this repository equal to new repository.
And here I need to pass a parameter of type application.
Here's the problem where I can get the application, get application context, the view dot, get application
context.
Nothing I can use to get the application instance.
So the solution is to change from view model to Android view model.
Android View Model class is a subclass of a view model and similar to them they are designed to store
and manage UI related data that are responsible to prepare and provide data for the UI and automatically
allow data to survive configuration changes so I can use a new constructor.
Alt+ Insert constructor my repository and you can see my application is passed.
Okay, so this constructor will get application and a repository.
I'll remove this repository because I need to initialize it here equal to new repository and pass the
application as a parameter.
So this is how we use the Android view model.
Again, Android view model is a subclass of view model that are designed to store and manage UI related
data.
Then I need to create the live data.
And this live data instance, all contacts will call the repository dot, get all contacts method this
method, get all contacts and return the data and store it inside the live data.
So public live data of type list of contacts data type Get all contacts then all contacts.
Live data equal to repository dot get all contacts.
You can see I'm using the repository to get all contacts and execute this method, return all contacts.
Also I have inside this repository to other methods.
Add contact and delete contact.
So I'll use ViewModel to create these methods and call the methods of the repository public void.
Add new contact and I need to pass a contact object.
You can see I'm using my repository instance to call and execute the functions.
Add contact public void delete contact.
I need to pass contacts object and use it in order to execute the repository, delete contact method
and pass the contact.
So this class will provide the data to the UI.
Live data is used to observe changes in the user data and automatically update the UI when data changes
and contacts can be inserted into room database through the ViewModel and also be deleted.
This Mvvm architecture separates concerns, makes the code more maintainable and ensures a responsive
and up to date UI.
The ViewModel acts as a bridge between the UI and the data source, which is the room database in our
application, making it easier to manage data and UI interactions.