We finished the room database repository and the view model.
So we finished the model and the view model sections of the Mvvm.
Now let's move to create our view.
The view represents the user interface of an application.
It includes everything the user can see and interact with, such as UI components, layouts, widgets
and screens.
It defines how the data from the view model is presented to the user.
The view handles user interactions such as button clicks, text input and gestures when a user interacts
with the UI.
The view communicates these actions to the ViewModel.
The View observes live data or other observable data sources provided by the View model.
Live data allows the view to automatically update itself when the underlying data changes, providing
real time updates to the user.
Ideally, the view should not contain business logic or data retrieval code.
Instead, it delegates these responsibilities to the view model.
The separation of concerns helps maintain code, clarity and testability.
So in summary, the view in an Mvvm architecture is responsible for presentation of data and user interactions.
While the View model manages the underlying data, business logic and the communication between the
model and the View.
So let's jump into Android studio and start building our layouts and activities.
Main activity.
Go split mode and remove this text view.
In this example I'll use data binding.
So for that I'll go to the build.gradle and here I'll add the data binding dependency or enable it inside
the Android scope.
I need to add build features data binding equal to true sync.
The project.
Now we're able to use data binding.
So here I'll start with layout tag and I'll move all of these.
Into the layout, and I'll move these namespaces to the layout here.
And inside this constraintlayout I'll create a recycler view and a fab floating action button.
Add the constraints, you can infer it.
Or drag and drop like this.
This is our recycler view.
I'll create a fab floating action button.
Wrap content.
And this is a small button I'll drag and drop it to here and infer the constraints ensuring that from
the end is 16 deep margin and from the button is 60.
And this is our fab floating action button.
It's just a simple button.
This will direct us to the add new contact activity.
Now let's move and create a new layout file.
I'll name it as contact underscore list item and this will be the template and the layout for every
contact in our application.
Of course I'll use the data binding.
So I'll start with the layout.
And move these and the namespaces move them to the layout.
And this is our constraint layout.
Inside this constraint layout, I'll create two text views, one for the name and one for the email
of the contact.
I'll start with the text view.
And this is our layout to text views.
I'll add margin here, 16 dpi for the whole constraint layout and the height would be wrap content.
So this is our contact list item template for every item in the database.