Since I'm going to use this layout, the contact list item, that XML file to display the items of the
database into a recycler view.
With this customized layout, I need to use a custom adapter that extends from recycler view and contains
a view holder.
So for that I'll create a new Java class.
I'll name it as my adapter.
And this my adapter class will act as a custom adapter for our recycler view.
I'll extend recycler view dot adapter and you can see I need to pass the H viewholder class and the
main purpose of a view holder is to hold references to views that are part of the individual items layout
within a recycler view.
These views can be complex, containing multiple widgets like text, view, image, view and more.
In our case, we have only two text views we need to display.
A recycler view can potentially display a large number of items and creating a new view for each item
can be resource intensive and slow The Viewholder pattern.
The addresses this issue by recycling and reusing views for different items.
As they scroll on and off the screen, please refer to the recycler view section.
If you have any doubt here, I need to pass the view holder and always when you create a custom adapter,
start by creating the view Holder class.
I'll start by class View Holder extends from recycler view dot view holder.
I need to extend from the recycler view dot Viewholder.
I need to hold the references here so private text, view, name and email.
But wait, why we're going to make like this and we're going to use and we use the data binding in our
layout.
So in this video I want from you to focus with me because this is a very new and very important concept
in Android data binding library.
I'm going to use the data binding with recycler view.
I don't need to write like this.
I'm going to create a reference for my item binding.
As I told you in the data binding library lessons, I'll start to to make the reference for this layout.
I need to start with the name of the layout with capital letter and the camel case and I'll add the
postfix or the keyword binding.
So contact list item contact list item and I'll use the binding keyword.
This is the first step and we know it.
Okay.
Alt+ enter to import this class, then I'll name it as contact list item bind.
I need to create a constructor and I don't need this view.
I need to pass it as contact list item binding dot get route and this method get route is a method used
to obtain the route view of the layout associated with a data binding instance.
It returns the route view of the layout associated with that binding object and in other words, it
provides access to the top level view in your layout XML file.
So it's a convenient way to access and interact with the route view of data bound layout in Android
allowing you to perform operations on the UI defined in your layout files.
Then back to up here I'll start adding the methods and the variables here.
So private array list of contacts object and name it as contacts, array list or contacts.
Alt+ enter import the class.
The second step is to pass this Viewholder here so I refer to my adapter dot contact Viewholder class
and I need to implement the methods Alt+ enter implement the methods we have to implement on create
Viewholder on bind Viewholder and get item count.
If you have any doubt about these methods, please refer to the Recyclerview section in our course.
But don't worry, I'll make an overview for each method.
I need to create an array list of type contacts and I need to create a constructor having this array
list.
Then I'll move to these methods.
I'll start with the Oncreate Viewholder on create Viewholder method is called by the recycler view when
it needs to create a new Viewholder to represent an.
Item in the list or the grid.
It's typically called when there is no recycled view holders available for reuse.
Example During the initial creation of items or when scrolling brings new items into view, this method
takes two parameters one of type view group and one of type integer.
This parent is a viewgroup representing the parent view that the view holders layout will be attached
to and the view type is of type an integer that represents the type of a view to be created.
This is useful when you have multiple view types in recycler view and you need to distinguish between
them and inside the Oncreate view holder method.
You need to inflate the layout for the items views and create a new instance of your custom view holder
class.
For that, I'll use a layout inflator, so I'll start with the content list item binding.
I'll create a new instance from it equal to data binding util dot inflate.
I want from you to focus with me because we didn't use the data binding class with the recycler view
in the data binding lesson.
So in this example, in this layout and in this app, I'm going to use the data binding with a recycler
view.
Please pay attention.