Data binding util dot inflate method is provided by the Android's data binding library Android X data
binding for inflating a layout and creating a binding object.
And inside this inflate method I need to pass four parameters.
The first one is layout inflator dot from parent dot get context.
It creates an instance of layout inflator associated with the context of the parent view group.
The layout inflator is used to inflate XML layouts into view objects.
Again, if you have any doubt or you need more information about layout inflator, please refer to the
recycler view section.
Then I need to pass the layout, the custom layout that I need to display as items of the recycler view.
So r dot layout dot contact list item.
This is the resource ID of the layout XML file you want to inflate.
The third parameter is the parent.
This parameter specifies the parent view group to which the inflated layout should be attached.
The inflated layout becomes a child of the parent view group.
The last parameter is a boolean fold and this case is false.
This parameter indicates whether to attach the inflated layout to the parent view group immediately
when set it to false.
The inflated layout is not attached to the parent at this point.
This is often the case when inflating layouts for recycler view items because recycler view manages
the attachment when necessary.
Then I need to return a new contact Viewholder contact list item binding passed as parameter returning
a Viewholder and passing the item binding as parameter.
The second method is on bind Viewholder on bind Viewholder method is called by the recycler view when
it needs to display or update an item at a specific position in the list or grid.
It's called for each visible item as you scroll through the recycler view and is responsible for updating
the items view within the data for that position, the parameters are to one of type contact Viewholder.
And this parameter is the Viewholder object for the item at the specified position, it holds references
to the views within the items layout.
The second parameter is of type integer.
This parameter indicates the position of the item in the recycler view's data source.
For example, an array list or data source cursor.
And in this case it's an array list.
So inside the on bind viewholder you use the holder parameter to access the views within the items layout.
For example, in our case we have two text views.
So I specify holder dot name or email, but since I'm using data binding so I need to use this contact
list item binding object to get the references and need to display or update an item at a specified
position.
For that, I'll make a contact object.
Current contact dot get index at position here.
I'm getting the current contact, then I'll use holder dot contact dot set contact to current contact
again on bind.
Viewholder is used to display or update an item at a specific position in the list.
This method determines the total number of items in the data set that will be displayed in the recycler
view.
So this method is used to specify the total number of items that the recycler view should display.
And in our case, I need to get the size of the contacts list that we created and here I need to check
if contacts array list doesn't equal to null, then go and return contacts dot size, otherwise it will
return zero.
So this is how we create the adapter and how we link the recycler view with data bind.
And one last thing I need to mention and add is the notify data set changed here.
I need to use public void set contacts.
This is the setter of this array list.
Or you can simply add like this alt+ insert setter and this contacts array list.
Under this I'll use notify data set changed method notify data set.
Changed method is a method provided by recycler view adapter class to inform the.
That recycler view that the underlying data set has changed and the recycler view should refresh its
views to reflect these changes.
It tells the recycler view that the data has changed and that it should rebind the views, possibly
creating new views and updating existing ones.
You typically call notify data set changed method after making changes to the data source that the recycler
view is displaying.
So this is our adapter class that extends from recycler view and we learned about how to use data binding
with the recycler view.