Welcome back.
Let's continue with the view layer of the Mvvm architecture.
And in this video, we're going to display all the data, all the contacts received from the room database
into the main activity recycler view.
For that, I need to define data, sources, adapters and binding objects.
Starting by data source.
I need to make a contact database object named as contact database and I'll create an array list of
contacts objects.
Here I need to create an object of adapter class private my adapter and here I need to create objects
for data binding.
I have two variables one for the activity main binding, main binding and one for the click handler
which we created before main activity Click handlers.
And this is the class that we created before that handles the click events on the Fab Floating Action
button.
Let's initialize them here in the Oncreate method.
Main binding equal to data binding util dot Setcontentview this and passing our dot layout dot activity
main data binding util dot Setcontentview is a method provided by Android's data binding library that
allows you to set the content view of an activity or a fragment with data binding enabled.
It simplifies the process of using data binding to bind UI elements to data sources in your layout XML
files.
Then I need to initialize the handlers equal to new main activity handlers and I'll pass this as a context.
Then I need to link the main activity binding dot set click handler to the handlers.
So here I am linking this main activity click handlers to the main activity binding.
Let's move to initialize our recycler view and define the layout manager for it.
Recycler View Recycler View equal to activity Main binding dot recycler View Recycler View Dot Set Layout
Manager.
New linear layout manager passing this and recycler view dot set has fixed size to true.
In this line, I am obtaining a reference to a recycler view widget from a layout that uses data binding
in Android.
This is called main binding, so this is an object that uses and refers to this activity.
Underscore main.
And I'm going to use a reference for the recycler view called recycler view here.
So this line is used to obtain a reference to a recycler view widget from a layout that uses data binding
in Android.
This reference allows you to interact with and manipulate the recycler view programmatically in your
Android application code using the data binding library.
Then let's move to create the adapter equal to new my adapter and I'll pass contacts as an array list.
Let's move to the database contact database equal to contact database dot get instance and I need to
pass the context get instance.
As I told you before in the contact database, it will return one instance of the contact database because
we followed the singleton pattern.
Then I need to use the view model.
So I'll create my ViewModel instance.
ViewModel New ViewModel provider this dot get my view model dot class.
So this line of code is used to get and create and retrieve an instance of a ViewModel associated with
a specific activity or fragment.
Let's break it down.
ViewModel Provider is a class provided by Android's ViewModel architecture component.
It's used to create and manage view models within the scope of an activity or fragment.
This keyword typically refers to the current activity or fragment instance in the context of your code.
This is passed as an argument to the view model provider.
It signifies that you want to create or retrieve a ViewModel associated with the current activity or
fragment.
The get method of ViewModel Provider is called with a class of the ViewModel you want.
This method is responsible for creating a new instance of the ViewModel if it doesn't already exist
or returning an existing instance.
If it does, then I'll insert a new contact just for testing.
Later on we'll create a new activity that it's.
Responsible for creating and inserting new contacts into the database.
I'll start with the contacts.
New contact.
The ID would be one.
This not important because the database.
The database will auto generate the primary key.
Then the name would be Jack and the email is Jack at gmail.com.
I need to insert it into our database, so I'll use view model dot add new contact.
You can see I am dealing with the view model.
I don't deal directly with the database, I deal with the view model and the view model will deal with
the repository and the repository will deal with the room database.
This is how the Mvvm architecture works.
Then I need to use the recycler view dot set adapter linking the adapter with the recycler view adapter
and before linking the recycler view, I need to load the data from the database.
What I need to do is.
View model dot.
Get all contacts.
Then I need to use the observe method and the observe method is used to observe or listen for changes
in the underlying data held by the live data object.
You use the observe method on a live data object and pass in an observer you created.
The Observe method establishes a connection between the live data and the observer.
It tells the live data to notify the observer when the data changed.
I need to pass two parameters one for the owner and one for the observer.
So I am linking here the Observer with the observe, and I'm going to override the on changed method,
and the observer object defines the behavior to execute when the user live data changes.
In this case, it's reacting to changes in the context data.
I'll use a for loop for each loop it's of type context.
See inside the contacts array list.
At first I'll get them into the logcat and then display them into the recycler view.
So for that I'll make log dot v tag and c dot get name.
I'll display all the names of the contacts in my database.
Let's run this application and test our code.