And congratulations, guys.
This is our application displaying Jack as a contact from our room database.
But there is a problem if I run the application again with the ID equal to one, it will cause an error
because I'm specifying the ID and in room database.
It's a unique identifier, so I need to remove it and go to the contacts constructor and remove the
ID from here because the room database will do this job and autogenerate new contacts with the new IDs.
Run the program and it will solve the problem again.
Then I'll move to the main activity and I need to display the contacts into the recycler view.
So for that I need to refill this ArrayList.
I need to assign this contact array list in the unchanged method Contacts array list dot add C so every
contact in the contacts list, go and add it to the contacts array list.
I need to move these lines.
The adapter.
Under the ViewModel.
Observe Contacts.
Array list.
Let me run the application.
And we have this null pointer exceptions.
I can resolve them by changing here the contacts list, remove it and.
Okay.
I need to initialize it at first, so I'll scroll and I need to initialize a new array list.
Run it again.
And here we go.
This is our application.
It's working fine.
If I search for Tag and I can see the contacts.
So every time I run the application, it will create a new jack with a different ID and insert it into
our database.
And the most important trick here is to notify the data that recycler view with the new data.
So I'll use my adapter dot notify data set changed method inside ViewModel dot observe method.
This is the most important part here.
In order to display the data from logcat into the items of the recycler view, so notify data set.
Changed method is a method provided by recycler views adapter to notify the recycler view that are underlying
data has changed and the recycler view should refresh its views to reflect these changes.
This method is often used when you've made changes to the data resource and you need the recycler view
to display this change and you need to ensure that the UI is updated accordingly.
Let's stop the application and run it again.
And the Congratulations guys.
We succeeded in displaying the items of the recycler view from the room database.