Welcome back.
In this video, I'll mention a very important concept, which is how to get the data from edit text
and pass them to the main activity using data binding and using the intents, of course.
So I want from you to focus with me.
For that I'll create a new variable called Click Handler.
And the type of this variable is a new class that I'll created.
Now add new contact Click Handler.
This class will handle the click events on this button and direct the user from this activity to the
main activity.
Getting the name and the email from edit text.
For that, I'll create a contact object in order to pass the name and the email to it and assign them.
And I need a context object because I am going to use the intents.
I'll create the constructor having these two variables and I'll create a new method called on Submit
button.
Click.
Don't miss to pass a view as an object.
This is for data binding.
Always make sure when you are going to execute any method, you should add the view as a parameter.
Then let's check if contact dot get name doesn't equal to or equal equal to null or contact dot get
email equal equal to null.
I don't need to make anything.
I need to display an error message telling him that fields can't be empty.
Else I need to pass the data from the edit text to the main activity.
So else here I need to start intent.
I equal to new intent and I'll use the context object that I created to get the current destination
context.
And next destination is the main activity dot class.
And I mentioned this in the intent section.
I need to put extra to put more information to this intent.
I equal to put extra and here I'll pass key value pairs one for the name and one for the email.
And the name and the email.
Two variables are of type string.
The key of the name would be name and the value of it.
It's get it from the context dot get name and I dot put extra the key of the email is email and make
sure that you'll type them later on in the main activity.
In the same way you type the key because you need to specify the key and it's a case sensitive to get
the value context dot get email.
Then I need to start the activity context dot start activity and I need to pass I.
Now the last step is to link the data binding with function that we created here on submit button.
Click and link the edit text with the contact object.
Here I'll create.
Com dot master coding context manager app and here I need to specify add new contact click handler.
Then let's move down to the edit text here.
It's very important step to specify text equals and when using two way binding, you should mention
this equal sign contact dot name and the second edit text is text at equals contact dot email.
Then let's move to the button.
And here we should mention onClick attribute at without the equal sign handler to Collins on submit
button click.
The last step is to move to the Add new Contact Activity class and initialize the data binding private
activity.
Add the new contact binding binding, and I need to create an instance from the class that we created
for the click handling.
Object type cont.
Then I'll move to the Oncreate method.
Contacts equal to new contacts equals data binding util dot setcontentview.
And here I need to specify the layout or dot layout dot add new count.
This refers to the context of this add new contact activity.
Then I need to set the contact.
I need to pass this contact object and to pass it to the binding binding dot set contact to contacts.
This is a very important step.
Many people miss this.
I need to create and initialize the handler new add, new contact handler and I need to pass two parameters.
The first one is the context and the context of the Add new contact activity.
And the second parameter is the contacts object that we created before.
I need to switch between them because the first one is the context and the second is the context.
Then I need to link this handler with the data binding.
So set click handler to handle.
What we've done here is to create and initialize the binding the handler and to create a new object
called contacts and assign it to this variable.
And the click handler is passed here and assigned to this by using set click handler.
Let's run, click on this fab.
If I don't add anything, fields can't be empty.
Those messages will appear.
I'll add John john@gmail.com click add contacts to room and here we go.
We are directed to the main activity and having the intent extra, which is the name and the email.
In the next videos we're going to insert email and name that we passed here into our database.