Welcome back.
Instead of sending the name and the email to the main activity and the main activity will create a contact
and send it to the database we're going to use the ViewModel instance passed from the Add new contact
activity to the Add new contact Click handler and use it to insert it into our database.
So there is no need to put extra because this method using the intents and put extra will cause some
errors when calling the main activity and sending it and the main activity will insert the database.
I'll commend this and I'll show you a better approach.
I'll create a new ViewModel instance in the add new contact activity before the handler.
My ViewModel, my ViewModel equals new ViewModel provider and I'll pass this as the owner dot get and
here I need to get my ViewModel class here.
I'm getting an instance of the ViewModel here.
I'll pass it my view mode.
Let's go to the constructor of this add new contact handler and I'll create my ViewModel, my ViewModel.
Why I'm doing this?
Why I can't create my ViewModel directly here.
My ViewModel equal to new my ViewModel provider.
And here you can't pass this because you need an activity or fragment.
And this class is not extending from the appcompat or any activity.
So for that you need to pass the ViewModel in the constructor and then use it here.
You understand?
Guys, I want from you to focus with me in this idea.
I'm changing the constructor and creating my ViewModel instance just to solve this error.
Because when you create a My ViewModel, you need to pass inside the ViewModel provider as a ViewModel
store owner and this is passed from an activity or fragment exclusively.
So for that I remove this line and here I'll change the constructor.
My ViewModel, this dot, my ViewModel equal to my ViewModel.
Now my ViewModel is passed from add new contact activity.
I'll use this ViewModel in order to insert this information about the name and email of the contact
and create a new contact object.
I'll name it, see new contacts and I'll set contact dot get name and contact dot get email.
I need to insert this contact using ViewModel, my ViewModel dot add new contact and I'll pass.
See again guys.
When dealing with viewmodels, please pay attention to create an instance from it and pass it to the
classes that acts as click handlers here.
This class is not extending from appcompat activity, so this class is a normal class, not an activity.
This is an activity.
So inside the activity I can use ViewModel and create instances from ViewModel.
Let me run go to this activity and I'll name it as Richard Richard at Gmail, Click add contact to the
database and here we go.
We are directed to the main activity and Richard contact is added to our database.
Congratulations, guys.
We succeeded in inserting data into our database using an instance of my ViewModel passed to the constructor
of the Click Handler class.