Let's learn how to implement swipe to delete functionality to the recycler view.
But at first I need to create card views for the items and change the background of our application.
I'll create here inside the contact list item a card view Matchparent Wrap content and inside this card
view implement my constraint layout so I copy this and move it inside our card.
View this constraint layout that contains the two text views.
Here I'll add elevation 20 DPI, corner radius 20 DPI and I'll add some margin margin left and right,
20 DPI and margin top five DPI margin.
Bottom five DPI.
It's good.
The cards here is the width should be zero and here zero DPI.
Okay.
It's good.
If we run the application it looks better with the card views.
I'll copy this background and paste it in the drawable folder and you can see it.
It's very beautiful.
Let's make it our main activity background.
And here in the constraint layout, set the background back to and it's very simple and classic application.
Let's design this fab drawable folder and the new vector asset, and here I'll name it as Ik add clip
art.
Click on this and search for Add and I'll use this sign click.
Okay, you can change the color.
I'll set it to red next and click finish.
Then add the background tint black and source compat android src and select it baseline underscore at
24.
I remove this background and it's better.
Now you can see the plus sign.
And let's move to start deleting items from the database when the user swipe the items in the recycler
view open main activity and here under the recycler view dot set adapter I'll implement swipe to delete
functional new item touch helper new item touch helper and select simple callback method and you'll
implement two methods on move and on swipe.
Now let's explain itemtouchhelper.
New Itemtouchhelper is used to create an instance of Itemtouchhelper, which is a utility class in Android
that provides support for handling touch gestures, especially for swipe and drag and drop actions in
a recycler view or similar view.
The constructor of Itemtouchhelper.
A simple callback takes two arguments.
The first argument is zero.
In this case specifies the drag and drop directions.
Zero means no drag and drop is supported.
The second argument is Itemtouchhelper dot left specifies the swipe directions.
In this case it indicates the swiping items to the left is supported.
So I'm going to swipe the items to the left in order to delete them and we override it.
Two methods.
The first one is on move.
This method is called when an item in recycler view is moved as part of a drag and drop operation.
And in this case I'll not use it on swipe.
This method is called when a recycler view item is swiped by the user.
Parameters.
Viewholder and direction Viewholder the viewholder of the item that was swiped and direction and integer
indicating the swipe direction left or right and inside the method you define the action to be taken
when an item is swiped.
So if you swipe the item to the left, what I need to do, I need to delete this item.
So contacts C equals to contacts array list dot get viewholder dot get adapter position get adapter
position method is a method that is provided by the Viewholder class.
It returns the adapter position of the item associated with the Viewholder.
The adapter position represents the item's position within the data set that the recycler view is currently
displaying.
It can change if the items are added, removed or rearranged in the adapters data source and get method
is typically used to retrieve data from a data source such as an array list in our case.
So I'm getting the swiped item.
Then I need to execute the method delete contact.
I need to use view model dot delete contact and here I need to pass the contact that I get it its position.
Then I need to add a very important thing here.
Dot attach to recycler view recycler view.
This method attached to recycler view is used with Android's Itemtouchhelper class to attach it to a
recycler view.
It associates the itemtouchhelper with the recycler view, enabling it to handle swipe and drag and
drop gestures for the items within the recycler view.
Let's run.
This is our great application.
Now let's try to swipe the recycler view and you can see I deleted Richard contact from our application.
Let me close all applications and then run it to test our database.
And you can see Jack and James are still Richard is deleted.
Congratulations, guys.
We succeeded in adding the delete functionality to our app.
Location using swipe to delete.